Guide to the HASTAC Records 1989-2017 UA.26.03.0025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
HASTAC Records
1989-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Humanities, Arts, Science and Technology Advanced Collabratory (HASTAC)
UA.26.03.0025
10 Linear Feet
General office files including correspondence, website captures, articles, conference materials, clippings, bound publications, t-shirts, and other materials.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Historical Note
HASTAC ("haystack") is a consoritum of humanists, artists, social scientists, scientists, and engineers committed to new forms of collaboration across communities and disciplines fostered by creative uses of technology.
Collection Overview
General office files including correspondence, website captures, articles, conference materials, clippings, bound publications, t-shirts, and other materials.
Related Materials
Cathy N. Davidson Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Humanities, Arts, Science, and Technology Advanced Collaboratory (HASTAC), 2010-ongoing, in the University Archives Web Archive Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Interdisciplinary approach in education; Humanities, Arts, Science and Technology Advanced Collabratory (HASTAC); Davidson, Cathy N., 1949-
- UA2010.0021, 1
  - Davidson article on photography, 4 folders (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until 2032
  - Technology (including photocopies of articles and book chapters), 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Women and Technology (including photocopies of articles and book chapters), 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Photography (including photocopies of articles and book chapters), 15 folders (Box 1)
  - unlabeled general office files, 28 folders (Box 1)
  - Humanities Lab, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - "Closing: The Life and Death of an American Factory" by Bill Banberger and Cathy N Davidson, book and brochures (Box 2)
  - HASTAC general office files and conference materials, 14 folders (Box 2)
  - General office files, 15 folders (Box 2)
  - Course readers, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Slides and general office files (Box 2)
  - Promotional brochures (Box 2)
  - Academic Affairs Committee, 2004 May 07 (Box 3)
    Restricted until 2029
  - Conference folders (Box 3)
  - Conference planning documents (Box 3)
  - Publicity information (Box 3)
  - Foundation information (Box 3)
  - Clippings (Box 3)
  - Duke University Reports (Box 3)
  - Photographs and electronic materials (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Floppy disks and optical disks (CDs)
- UA2017.0027, 2
  - General Files, 2.1
    - HASTAC '07 notes, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Conference budget costs, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Call for papers and panels HASTAC '07, 2006 (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2031
    - Conference services, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Dan Connolly, 2006 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC '07 general, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Ruseel Gunn, 2006 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC Info 2006-2007 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC '07 Performance Proposals, 2006 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC Tech Meetings, 2006 (Box 4)
    - TSS Workshop Evaluations, undated (Box 4)
    - Other humanities proposals, 2006 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC 2008-2009 (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2034
    - HASTAC website redesign, 2008 (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2033
    - Mellon Foundation proposal: Digital Innovation Fellowships, November 2008 (Box 4)
    - IMLS Laura Bush 21st Century Librarian Application: Jared Mostafa, 2008 (Box 4)
    - NEH Fellowships @Digital Humanities Centers Proposals, 2008-2009 (Box 4)
    - NEH Fellowships @Digital Humanities Centers Proposals, 2008 (Box 4)
    - Melinda Gates, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Nicholas Gessler, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Global Kids Rez Ed Reports, 2008 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC website 2005-2006 development (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2030
    - NSF: HASTAC, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Possible HASTAC Partners, 2005 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC MacArthur Foundation, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Project summary, 2005 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC website, 2005 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC budget, 2005 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC-WWF proposal, 2004 (Box 4)
    - WWF-HASTAC, 2004 (Box 4)
    - NSF final proposal, 2003 (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2028
    - HASTAC IV emails, 2004 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC powerpoint, undated (Box 4)
    - HASTAC vision statement letter, 2004 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC: Duke contacts and others for invitation list, 2003 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC grant submitted, 2003 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC 3D project, Sikh's, undated (Box 4)
    - HASTAC group research meeting in Seattle, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Info on Global Grid forum, Humanities and Social Sciences, 2003 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC conference at Duke, Fall 2003 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Press Release, 2003 (Box 4)
    - HASTAC, July 2005 (Box 4)
    - Summary and agenda, 2003 April 28 (Box 4)
    - UCHRA Technology, 2003 June 5-6 (Box 4)
    - Thinking Through New Media Graduate Student Conference, ISIS/HASTAC/RENCI, 2006 June 7-8 (Box 4)
    - Interdisciplinary Infrastructure, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Knight, 2010 (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2035
    - MacArthur, 2006 (Box 4)
    - 2010 Steering Committee meeting at UNC (Box 4)
    - IMPS (Franklin Center Gaming Room), 2007 (Box 4)
    - DMLC3, 2008 (Box 4)
    - Competition Grant Proposal, 2007 (Box 4)
    - MacArthur Grant, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Future of Learning Close Out (Duke), 2008 (Box 4)
    - MAKN, 2011 (Box 4)
      Restricted until 2036
    - MAKN Approval, 2011 (Box 4)
    - Master's in Knowledge and Networks (MKN), 2011 (Box 4)
    - Mellon: Making the Humanities Central, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    - Visual Studies Initiative, 2006 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Agendas, 2007-2008 (Box 5)
    - Argentina, 2001 (Box 5)
      Restricted until 2026
    - Bellagio Fellowship with Rockefeller Foundation, 2006 (Box 5)
    - HASTAC-FHI MOU, 2011-2013 (Box 5)
      Restricted until 2038
    - MOU, 2011 (Box 5)
    - HASTAC 2 Conference, 2008 May 22-24 (Box 5)
    - HASTAC Scholars, 2008-2009 (Box 5)
    - DML Competition Year 3, 2009-2010 (Box 5)
    - Digital Media Learning Competition, 2007-2008 (Box 5)
    - DML 3, 2010 (Box 5)
    - DML 2 and 3, 2008 (Box 5)
    - HASTAC 2007 Conference Proceedings (Box 5)
    - HASTAC 20087-2008 Staff Debriefing, 2007 January (Box 5)
    - DML Year 1 Finalists, 2008 (Box 5)
    - Inquiries and Responses Year 1, 2007 (Box 5)
    - DML, 2007-2008; and CD (Box 5)
    - Two Bits, 2008 (Box 5)
    - Conference Registration and Attendance, 2007 (Box 5)
    - Conference Program, 2007 (Box 5)
    - NSF Expanding Cyber-communities proposal login information, 2005 June (Box 5)
    - RENCI, 2006 (Box 5)
    - Mellon Foundation Sawyer Seminar, 2003-2007 (Box 5)
    - Press Pictures, 2001, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Laura Brown Ithaka, 2006 (Box 5)
    - UCHRI Board, 2003 (Box 5)
    - HASTAC-related projects, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Technology Confab, 2003 (Box 5)
    - UCHRI, 2000 (Box 5)
      Restricted until 2025
    - Promotional materials and brochures (Box 6)
    - HASTAC Steering Committee, 2009 April 20 (Box 7)
    - UC Riverside, 2000 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Demos and Exhibits, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Closing Reception, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Chapel Hill Conference running concurrently, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Samples from other conferences, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Advertising the conference, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Conference Folder Contents, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: Conference Participants, 2007 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning: HASTAC Budget '07, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Meeting Agendas and Note, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
    - InFormation Year sites' technology contracts, 2006 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Planning (Cathy email), 2000 July 18 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Brochure Final Printing, 2006 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC InFormation Year printed communications, 2006 (Box 7)
    - HASTAC InFormation, 2007 (Box 7)
    - InCOmmon, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, 2006 September (Box 7)
    - Interplay: Addendum to Letter of Agreement, 2006 October (Box 7)
    - Interaction, 2006 December (Box 7)
    - InJustice, University of Michigan Ann Arbor, 2007 January (Box 7)
    - Integration, Wayne State University, 2007 February (Box 7)
    - Invitation, University of Washington, 2007 March (Box 7)
    - HASTAC Durham Conference Planning, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Various HASTAC publications, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
    - 3590035 P3 Workshop, 2010 (Box 7)
    - DML Working Group: P3, 2009 (Box 7)
    - DML Workshop P3, 2010 (Box 7)
    - P3 Workshop, 2010 (Box 7)
    - Duke University Archives HASTAC Project, 2007 (Box 7)
    - EDUCAUSE San Diego, 2006 January (Box 7)
    - PR, 2007 (Box 7)
  - Mandy Dailey's files, 2.2
    - HASTAC Conference materials for distribution, 2007 (Box 7)
    - The Future of Learning Free Public Events, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Institute for the Future of the Book, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Libraries and Digital Archiving, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Editorial Proceedings, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Chronicle Review, HASTAC Web Statistics, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Future of Learning Final Report, 2008 (Box 7)
    - Future of Learning Inst. Mac I Grant, 2006 (Box 7)
    - Future of the Book, 2007-2008 (Box 7)
    - Steam Challenge Brochures, 2014 (Box 7)
      Restricted until 2039